# **Brandon Amos**

**☎** (540) 947 1238 • ⋈ bamos@cs.cmu.edu • 🕆 bamos.github.io Generated on October 21, 2016

I am a third-year Computer Science Ph.D. student at Carnegie Mellon University and am supported by an NSF graduate research fellowship. I spent the first two years of my Ph.D. working between mobile computing and machine learning and I now work with Zico Kolter on machine learning and optimization I am particularly interested in improving our understanding of important modeling problems in computer vision, language, and reinforcement learning through the use of deep learning, optimization (sometimes convex), theory, and statistics.

I strongly believe in open science and reproducible research and actively publish code on my Github profile. I am also the author of OpenFace, which is an open source face recognition project that uses deep learning.

#### Education

o Ph.D. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University	Aug 2014 – Present
o M.S. in Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University	Aug 2014 – May 2016
o B.S. in Computer Science, Virginia Tech (3.99/4.00)	Aug 2011 – May 2014
<ul> <li>Northside High School (Roanoke, Virginia)</li> </ul>	May 2011
Research Experience	

Research Experience	
<ul><li>Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Zico Kolter</li><li>Machine learning and optimization</li></ul>	Apr 2016 – Present
<ul> <li>Carnegie Mellon University, Prof. Mahadev Satyanarayanan</li> <li>Machine learning and mobile computing</li> </ul>	Aug 2014 – Apr 2016
<ul><li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Jules White</li><li>Mobile computing, cyber-physical systems, and security</li></ul>	May 2012 – May 2014
<ul><li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Layne Watson</li><li>Scientific computing, global/stochastic optimization, and bioinfor</li></ul>	Jan 2013 – May 2014 matics
<ul><li>Virginia Tech, Prof. Binoy Ravindran</li><li>Heterogeneous compilers</li></ul>	Nov 2012 – Mar 2014

### Selected Publications

- B. Amos, L. Xu, J. Z. Kolter, "Input convex neural networks," ArXiv preprint arXiv:1609.07152, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.07152.
- H. Zhao, T. Adel, G. Gordon, B. Amos, "Collapsed Variational Inference for Sum-Product Networks," in ICML, 2016. [Online]. Available: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~hzhao1/papers/ ICML2016/BL-SPN-main.pdf.
- [3] B. Amos, B. Ludwiczuk, M. Satyanarayanan, "Openface: A general-purpose face recognition library with mobile applications," Technical Report CMU-CS-16-118, CMU School of Computer Science, Tech. Rep., 2016. [Online]. Available: http://reports-archive.adm.cs.cmu.edu/anon/anon/ 2016/CMU-CS-16-118.pdf.
- B. Amos, D. Easterling, L. Watson, W. Thacker, B. Castle, M. Trosset, "QNSTOP-QuasiNewton Algorithm for Stochastic Optimization," 2014. [Online]. Available: https://vtechworks.lib.vt. edu/bitstream/handle/10919/49672/qnTOMS14.pdf.

# **Teaching Experience**

<ul> <li>Distributed Systems (CMU 15-440/640), TA</li> </ul>	S2016
<ul> <li>Software Design and Data Structures (VT CS 2114), TA</li> </ul>	S2013

## **Industry Experience**

<ul> <li>Data Scientist Intern, Adobe Research</li> </ul>	May 2014 – Aug 2014
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Snowplow Analytics</li> </ul>	Dec 2013 – Jan 2014
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Qualcomm</li> </ul>	May 2013 – Aug 2013
<ul> <li>Software Engineer Intern, Phoenix Integration</li> </ul>	May 2012 – Aug 2012
<ul> <li>Network Administrator Intern, Sunapsys</li> </ul>	Jan 2011 – Aug 2011

## **CMU Graduate Coursework**

o Advanced Machine Learning (10-715, Au), B. Poczos	F2016
o Intermediate Statistics (10-705, Au), L. Wasserman	F2016
o Topics in Deep Learning (10-807), R. Salakhutdinov	F2016
o Machine Learning (10-701, Au), T. Mitchell	S2016
o Computer Vision (16-720, Au), D. Ramanan	S2016
o Convex Optimization (10-725), R. J. Tibshirani	F2015
o Algorithms in the Real World (15-853), G. Blelloch and A. Gupta	F2015
<ul> <li>Semantics of Programming Languages (15-812), A. Platzer</li> </ul>	S2015
o Optimizing Compilers for Modern Architecture (15-745), T. Mowry	S2015
o Advanced Operating and Distributed Systems (15-712), D. Andersen	F2014
$\circ$ Mobile and Pervasive Computing (15-812), M. Satyanarayanan and D. Siewiorek	F2014

## **Honors & Awards**

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship	2016 - 2019
o 1st Place Undergraduate Senior Capstone Award, Virginia Tech Computer Scien	nce 2014
<ul> <li>David Heilman Research Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science</li> </ul>	2014
<ul> <li>Senior Scholar Award, Virginia Tech Computer Science</li> </ul>	2014
<ul> <li>Honorable Mention, CRA Outstanding Undergraduate Researcher Award</li> </ul>	2014
Awarded eight undergraduate merit scholarships	2011 - 2014

#### Skills

Languages	Bash, C, C++, CSS, Fortran, Haskell, HTML, Java, JavaScript, LATEX, Lua,
	Make, Mathematica, Python, R, Scala
Frameworks	Akka, Android SDK/NDK, Caffe, Node.js, NumPy, TensorFlow, Torch7, Pandas,
	SciPy, scikit-learn, Spark, Spray
Systems	Linux, OSX